<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipe>
 <name>Sablés salés</name>
 <subname>A savoury version of the sablé spritz</subname>
 <servings>15</servings>
 <prepTime icon="mixer.png">00:15</prepTime>
 <cookTime icon="oven.png">00:20</cookTime>
 <restTime></restTime>
 <coolTime>00:15</coolTime>
 <notes>You will need a piping bag or tool. If you are using De Guyer's &quot;Le Tube&quot; with a biscuit attachment, set it to 2cl output.</notes>
 <attribution>Liberally adapted from the sweet version.</attribution>
 <listIngredients>
  <ingredient_item id="0">
   <quantity>125</quantity>
   <unit>g</unit>
   <ingredient>margarine, at least 70% fat</ingredient>
  </ingredient_item>
  <ingredient_item id="1">
   <quantity>30</quantity>
   <unit>g</unit>
   <ingredient>yeast flakes</ingredient>
  </ingredient_item>
  <ingredient_item id="2">
   <quantity>20</quantity>
   <unit>ml</unit>
   <ingredient>soy, oat or almond milk</ingredient>
  </ingredient_item>
  <ingredient_item id="3">
   <quantity>120</quantity>
   <unit>g</unit>
   <ingredient>flour (T45)</ingredient>
  </ingredient_item>
  <ingredient_item id="4">
   <quantity>30</quantity>
   <unit>g</unit>
   <ingredient>cornstarch</ingredient>
  </ingredient_item>
  <ingredient_item id="5">
   <quantity>1</quantity>
   <unit>pinch</unit>
   <ingredient>salt</ingredient>
  </ingredient_item>
 </listIngredients>
 <listInstructions>
  <instruction id="0">Warm the oven to 180°C. Alternatively, you can do this latter, leaving your biscuits for a bit longer in the fridge.</instruction>
  <instruction id="1">Whip together the margarine and half the yeast flakes until creamy.</instruction>
  <instruction id="2">Add the milk little by little. Ideally it should form a consistent mixture, but it doesn't matter too much if not.</instruction>
  <instruction id="3">In another bowl, mix the rest of the yeast flakes, flour, cornstarch and salt.</instruction>
  <instruction id="4">Fold together the two mixtures, avoiding mixing too much so as to not develop the gluten.</instruction>
  <instruction id="5">Use a piping bag with a fluted nozzle to create the iconic spritz zig-zag shape directly onto a baking sheet covered with grease proof paper or a silicon sheet. Alternatively, you can use a special biscuit press to stamp out your biscuits. There are lots of options here.</instruction>
  <instruction id="6">Put the biscuits in the fridge for at least 5 minutes, preferably 15 minutes, probably no more than 30 minutes. This will help maintain their shape.</instruction>
  <instruction id="7">Transfer the biscuits to the oven and bake for 15-20 minutes.</instruction>
 </listInstructions>
</recipe>
